Josiah Kim

Denver, Colorado | (720) 840-3471 | josiahcwkim@gmail.com |linkedin.com/in/josiahkim | github.com/josiahckim/main

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Data Scientist with 4+ years of academic and professional experience in cleaning data, analyzing data, designing experiments, and presenting insights. Seeking a position involving shaping research and communicating findings. Skilled in research methodology, machine learning, optimization, and statistics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist II, CXO Performance Optimization

DISH Network | Englewood, CO | February 2022 - Present

- Created a web-scraping program to collect and analyze job listings to provide VPs with data-influenced recommendations to increase compensation for employees.
- Engineered a machine learning model to create a list of zip codes with the highest probabilities of producing the highest-performing and longest-tenured employees.
- Created an automatic resume parser to collect and analyze characteristics of high-performing and long-tenured employees.
- Initiated partnerships with other lines of business to address business problems and create data-influenced decisions.

Research Assistant

Penn State | University Park, PA | June 2021 - August 2021

- Coordinated with Professor Jeremy Ladd in an empirical study about opposition coalitions and democratization.
- Collected election data using Beautiful Soup, Requests, and Pandas within Python from over 2,900 Wikipedia pages.
- Identified problems within the existing Python and R scripts that reduced efficiency and caused data inconsistency.
- Created a program to assist with manually checking the collected data.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

CEO/Owner

SparkleBNB | Denver, CO | December 2018 - July 2022

- Maintained and built relationships with 14 clients looking for short-term rental turnover cleaning.
- Created an extensive screening process consisting of interviews and training to hire qualified individuals.
- Researched, designed, and implemented technical processes to make tasks more efficient.
- Implemented Profit First financial strategies to revenue over \$100,000.

Resident Assistant (RA)

Penn State Residence Life | University Park, PA | August 2019 – May 2021

- Supervised and consulted 43 first-year students during their day-to-day activities.
- Created and implemented 15 community-building activities each semester.
- Mediated conflict, facilitated resolutions, and engaged in difficult conversations with residents.

President

Alpha Rho Chi Fraternity | State College, PA | May 2020 - April 2021

EDUCATION

B.S. in Social Data Analytics; B.A. in Philosophy

The Pennsylvania State University | University Park, PA | 2017 - 2021

KEY SKILLS

Technical: Machine Learning, Web-Scraping, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing, Data Visualization, Research Design, Big Data, ETL **Programming**: Python, R, SQL, Java, JavaScript, Scala

Soft: Stakeholder Management, Storytelling, Curiosity, Time Management